<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section
  xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
  xml:id="setup_ide">

	<title>Setting up a configuration environment</title>

	<para>
		Since Eclipse SCADA is based on Java and Eclipse, both have to be
		installed to get it to run. In this chapter we will show how to install
		Java, Eclipse and all necessary plugins to get started. 
	</para>
	
	<section xml:id="setup_ide_java">
		<title>Installing Java</title>
		
		<para>
			At the time of writing Java 8 was just released, so the current version
			which is still in use in conjunction with Eclipse SCADA is Java 7.
			Java 8 should theoretically work, but it is not tested so far.
		</para>
		
		<section>
			<title>On Windows</title>
			
			<para>
				The recommended way on Windows is to use the official Java
				installation package provided by Oracle. The download site
				is to be found at: <link xlink:href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index-jsp-138363.html">http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/index-jsp-138363.html</link>.
				We recommend that you install Java for the same architecture
				as your system is. That means if you have a 64bit Windows, then also
				install the 64bit version of Java. If you have a 32bit Windows, you 
				have to install the 32bit version of Java as well. It is possible 
				to install the 32bit Version Java on a 64bit Windows, but unless 
				you have important reasons to do that, we will not recommend it.
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<title>On Linux</title>
			
			<para>
				The default Java package for most Linux distributions is the OpenJDK.
				To install the OpenJDK for your flavor of Linux use the package
				management tool of your distribution and install the package
				<filename>openjdk-7-jdk</filename> (the name of the package might be 
				slightly different depending on your distribution, on Red Hat for 
				instance it is called <filename>java-1.7.0-openjdk-devel</filename>).
				The important thing is, to install the JDK and not the JRE.
				If you install Java via the package manager, you will automatically
				get the correct version for your architecture (32bit or 64bit).
			</para>
			
			<para>
				Alternatively you can install the official Java Version from Oracle.
				To switch between the installed versions use the command:
				<programlisting language="bash"><![CDATA[sudo alternatives --config java]]></programlisting>
			</para>
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<title>On MacOS X</title>
			
			<para>
				Please refer to the official documentation found at:
				<link xlink:href="https://www.java.com/de/download/help/mac_install.xml">https://www.java.com/de/download/help/mac_install.xml</link>
			</para>
		</section>
		
	</section>
	
	<section xml:id="setup_ide_eclipse">
		<title>Installing Eclipse</title>
	
		<para>
			The current version (0.1.0) of Eclipse SCADA is based on the Kepler 
			release (4.3). Although the following instructions might (and
			actually should) work  without change with the future Luna release,
			we recommend to stay with the Kepler release. For Release 0.2.0
			it is planned to ensure Java 8 compatibility and we will switch
			to the Luna release.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			Traditionally Eclipse comes as a simple ZIP file, which just has
			to be extracted to somewhere on the file system and can be run from
			there. Even though many Linux distributions will include Eclipse
			in its package repositories, we do not recommend to use those.
			Just download the Kepler from <link xlink:href="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/">http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/</link>
			or, if there is already a newer release available, it can always be
			downloaded from the archives: <link xlink:href="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/packages/release/kepler/sr2">http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/packages/release/kepler/sr2</link>.
			You have to download the same architecture as the Java Version you 
			installed.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			Unzip it to a directory of your choice. From there you can now start it.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Installing the Eclipse SCADA plugins</title>
	
		<para>
			Next step is to install the necessary plugins which contain the actual 
			Eclipse SCADA components. For this go to
            <menuchoice><guimenu>Help</guimenu><guimenuitem>Install New Software</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. 
			In the text box "Work with" just enter following URL: 
			<link xlink:href="http://download.eclipse.org/eclipsescada/updates/release/0.1.0/"/>
			Then select the "Eclipse SCADA IDE" category and click on "Next".
			The next screen should contain all the additionally selected 
			dependencies. Click on "Next" there as well. On the next screen 
			accept the Licenses and click on "Finish". After the installation 
			Eclipse requires a restart. Do that.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			Additionally you can now install the additional openSCADA components. 
			These contain the OPC and the SNMP adapters. This may be part of 
			the 0.2.0 release of Eclipse SCADA, but for now they have to be 
			downloaded from the openSCADA site. To install it just repeat the steps
			above with the URL <link xlink:href="http://repo.openscada.org/p2/org.openscada/R/1.2.0/"/>
			<footnote>
				<para>
					The release will not be ready until End of May, until then
					please use the integration build found under
					<link xlink:href="http://repo.openscada.org/p2/org.openscada/I/1.2.0/"/>
				</para>
			</footnote>
			and select the "OpenSCADA IDE" category.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			After a restart of your Eclipse IDE you are ready to start configuring
			the SCADA system. For this please read further in <xref linkend="chap_configuration" />.
		</para>
	</section>

</section>

