<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section
  xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd">
  
    <title>DA – Data Access</title>
    <para>
      The main purpose of the DA modules is to acquire data from
      various data sources and offer them other modules for processing or
      visualization. The basic idea is that the data is provided in simple
      scalar values instead of complex data structures. So instead of
      having a complex data structure for a component (e.g. a meteo
      station) that has wind speed, wind direction and several other
      values, there are simply 3 (or possibly more) analog values. The
      structure is created by the namespace instead of data structures.
    </para>
    <para>
      The advantage of this approach is that all values can be treated
      equally when they are processed. It also simplifies the process of
      subscribing to values.
    </para>
    <para>
      For example if one application is only interested in the wind
      speed it will only subscribe to that value. There is no need to get
      the full data structure or to split up that structure.
    </para>
    <para>
      On the other hand there are functionalities like the
      <quote>level alarm</quote>
      . It monitors a value, and if it exceeds a defined value range, it
      will create an alarm. Now since that functionally only works on a
      single analog value, it can work on data coming from any system,
      describe any state. No matter if it is wind speed, disk usage or warp
      core intermix ratio. It always works the same way.
    </para>

    <section>
      <title>Data Item</title>
      <para>
        The <quote>data item</quote>, is the structure containing that one single value. Other names
        that are commonly used are <quote>tag</quote>, <quote>data point</quote>.
      </para>
      <para>
        In Eclipse SCADA the data item consists of:
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>A unique ID</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>A primary value</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>An undefined list of a secondary values</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      <para>
        Each data item has its unique id inside the instance it is
        running. This means that behind one communication endpoint, the item
        is unique. However different communication endpoints (even in the
        same application), may have items with the same ID. So the
        combination of communication endpoint plus ID make the item globally
        unique.
      </para>
     
    </section>

</section>
