<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd">

	<title>Overview</title>

	<para>
  The Eclipse NeoSCADA system will install a number of applications and libraries. There it is
  recommended to use some package manager to install the whole system.
    </para>
    
    <para>
  The problem with the Windows platform is, that the MSI system does not provide an easy
  way to have package dependencies or automatic dependency resolution. Therefore
  the situation on Windows platforms is different. The configuration tool will create
  "ready-to-run" MSI packages, which contain the software and the configuration. 
    </para>
    
    <section>
      <title>Pre-Requisites</title>
      <para>
  Installing the Eclipse NeoSCADA systems requires:
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para>Administrative permissions (aka "root access")</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Java 7 (JRE)</para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
      </para>
      <para>
      In addition to the basic software packages that you can install
      using Eclipse NeoSCADA is not much fun without having a configuration
      for your system. So in addition to the basic software you will need
      some sort of configuration to deploy. The easiest way to create you
      own configuration is by using the configuration tool described under
      <xref linkend="chap_configuration"/>.
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Which platform to use?</title>
      <para>
  The question about the <quote>best</quote> platform will never be really answered.
  However there are two facts to consider:
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem><para>Eclipse NeoSCADA is tested mostly on the most recent Ubuntu LTS release, 64bit</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Client applications are most often used on Windows 7+ installations (32 or 64bit)</para></listitem>
  </orderedlist>
      </para>
      <para>
  The decision which platform to use is finally yours!
      </para>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <title>Processor architecture</title>
      <para>
  While most parts of Eclipse NeoSCADA are plain Java and therefore independent of the
  processor architecture or platform, this is not the whole truth.
      </para>
      <para>
  Some minor parts do depend on the architecture, and may it only be the fact that the
  resulting MSI package was created for a specific target architecture or one configuration
  file points to a path called <filename>lib64</filename> instead of <filename>lib</filename>.
      </para>
      <para>
  It is therefore important that on 64bit operating systems, also a 64bit Java virtual machine
  is being used.<footnote><para>Technically it is still possible to do otherwise. But don't complain if something goes wrong.</para></footnote>
      </para>
      
    </section>
    
</section>
