<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd">

  <title>Java Configuration</title>

  <para>
  These sub-sections cover the different aspects of the Java Virtual Machine required for
  executing Java based Eclipse SCADA Applications. 
  </para>

  <section><title>Locating the Java Virtual Machine</title>
  

  <note>
    <para>This section applies to <trademark>Unix</trademark> based systems.</para>
  </note>

  <para>
  By default Eclipse SCADA will install a set of shell scripts which manage starting and stopping
  the different Eclipse SCADA applications. These shell script will use the following mechanism to
  locate Java. 
  </para>
  
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem><para>If <envar>JAVA_HOME</envar> is set, it will be used</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>If <envar>JRE_HOME</envar> is set, it will be used</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Use the java virtual machine found on the path</para></listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  
  <note><para>If <envar>JAVA_HOME</envar> or <envar>JRE_HOME</envar> are set to a path
  that is not existing, the execution will fail. The scripts do not switch to the next
  possible option.</para></note>
  
  <para>
  The variables can either be set in the files <filename>/etc/sysconfig/eclipsescada</filename> or <filename>/etc/default/eclipsescada</filename>
  or using some system way for setting environment variables (e.g. <filename>/etc/profile.d</filename>).
  This is also the order of defining. This means that while you system may specific a JAVA_HOME already,
  it is possible to override for Eclipse SCADA using the <quote>sysconfig</quote> or <quote>default</quote> file.
  </para>
  
  <para>
  If neither environment variable is set, then the scripts will fall back to using the Java Virtual Machine from
  the <envar>PATH</envar>. This can normally be configured using the command <filename>update-java-alternatives</filename>. 
  </para>
  
  <warning><title>Java 7+</title><para>While it is possible to select a Java 6 (or earlier) JVM using <filename>update-java-alternatives</filename>
  or the environment variables, still Eclipse SCADA <emphasis>won't work</emphasis> with Java versions 6 or earlier.</para></warning>
  
  </section>
    
</section>
