<section
  xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
  xml:id="vi_scripting">

  <title>Scripting</title>

  <para>
    The visual interface can be made dynamic using JavaScript fragments. Several elements allow
    triggering events or call methods which me be implemented using JavaScript code fragments.
  </para>
  
  <para>
    Internally the JavaScript engine of the Java Virtual Machine will be used. Depending in the
    version of the Java virtual machine this can be <quote>Rhino</quote> (e.g. with Java 7)
    or <quote>Nashorn</quote> (e.g. with Java 8). Both variants are JavaScript, but for example
    the <code>importPackage</code> method will only be available in <quote>Rhino</quote>.
  </para>
  
  <note><para>Which JavaScript engine is actually used depends on which Java virtual machine
  runs the final application.</para>
  </note>
  
  <section><title>Script context</title>
  <para></para>
  </section>
  
  <section><title>Life Cycle</title>
  <para></para>
  </section>
  
  <section><title>Element controllers</title>
  <para>
  Each VI element (e.g. Rectangle, Image, …) is controlled by a corresponding controller class.
  The controller class realizes the actual element in the application. Also can the controller class
  be accessed from the script fragments and be used to manipulate the actual realized graphical element. 
  </para>
  
  <programlisting language="JavaScript"><![CDATA[var text = controller.getElement ( "myTextElement" );
text.setText ( "Hello World" );
text.setForegroundColor ( "#FF0000");
]]></programlisting>

  <para>
  Each element has a <quote>name</quote> attribute which must be unique for each symbol.
  The <varname>controller</varname> variable can be used to retrieve the controller of the element,
  by name, from the symbol controller. All public method of the controller can be called from
  the JavaScript fragment.
  </para>
  
  <para>
  In order to see a mapping table of which element is controlled by which controller, and to
  see a documentation of the controllers, open the Eclipse help system and navigate to
  <guimenu>Eclipse SCADA HMI</guimenu> / <guisubmenu>Reference</guisubmenu> / <guimenuitem>Scripting</guimenuitem>.
  </para>
  
  </section>
  

</section>