<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
	version="5.0">

	<title>Authentication</title>

<para>
Before any further authorization can be performed the system needs to know <emphasis>who</emphasis>
wants to perform an operation. Selecting a user and verifying the identity is the process called
<quote>authentication</quote>.
</para>

<para>
Eclipse SCADA uses a simple TCP client/server communication concept with the NGP and NET protocol. After the TCP
connection has been established the client side sends its user credentials to the server side. The server verifies
and remembers the authenticated user for the lifetime of the TCP connection or closes the TCP connection immediately.
Data subscription and control operation can only be performed after the user has been authenticated.
</para>

<para>
After the user has been authenticated it will be checked if the user has the right to connect to the server.
See also the section "authorization".
</para>

<para>
There are two ways of authenticating a user in Eclipse SCADA. The first, simple, mechanism is used for connector
modules (aka drivers). Each driver checks for a specific username and password combination during the logon
process described above. The server checks for the system property
<property>org.eclipse.scada.core.server.common.ServiceCommon.password</property> if is is set
the value will be used as password. The user name is not relevant but will be remembered by the server. If the
password is not set any user is allowed to connect to the service without authentication.
</para>

<para>
The second, more complex, way is used by OSGi based services (aka <quote>master server</quote> and <quote>hd server</quote> ). The server
will scan for authentication services using OSGi. All registered services will be consulted in the order of their
priority. When the first authentication service returns a valid user, this user will be used. If no service is found
or no service accepted nor rejected the user the user information will be <quote>anonymous</quote> and accepted. Although the
user might connect as anonymous during this step, access will be restricted by the authorization step afterwards
where it is checked if the user is allowed to log on.
</para>


</section>
