<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd"
	version="5.0">

	<title>Authorization</title>

<para>
Eclipse NeoSCADA has two different behaviors for connections to servers. One manual mode and one automatic mode.
The decision is done by the application which mode to use. It cannot be configured in the connection
string itself.  
</para>

<para>
The easier version is the manual mode. Establishing the connection is manually triggered (e.g. by 
a user) and manually closed. If the connections breaks, it simply stays closed. This mode is, for example, used
in the <productname>ESAC</productname> application. Connections are opened and closed on user request.
If the connection breaks, an error message displayed to the user and the connection stays closed until the
user re-opens.  
</para>

<para>
In automatic mode the application simply decides weather the connection should stay open or stay closed.
Eclipse NeoSCADA manages then the connection state and will trigger connect and disconnect calls automatically.
In most cases the application simply requests the connection to be open. This mode is primarily used
by the master server or the normal end user client.
</para>

<para>
When the connection is requested to be opened, the appropriate call is made to the connection itself. If the
connection break a re-connect will be triggered immediately. The time of this requested will be noted
and the next action (connect or disconnect) will be delayed by the quiet period. The default quiet
period is 10 seconds, but can be changed using the system property
<property>openscada.default.reconnect.delay</property> which holds the time in
<emphasis>milliseconds</emphasis>.
So if the connection breaks and the first reconnect fails, the next reconnect will not be tried until the quiet
period is over. After that the next connection attempt will be made.
</para>
</section>
