<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section
	xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/xsd/docbook.xsd">

	<title>Setting up a development environment</title>

	<para>
		The following sub section explain in brief detail on how to setup
		a development environment. Eclipse NeoSCADA is developed using the
		Eclipse Java
		IDE (JDT), still it possible to use other IDEs and
		development environments as well in order to use Eclipse NeoSCADA in your
		own applications.
	</para>

	<section>
		<title>Setting up with the Eclipse IDE</title>
		<para>See <xref linkend="setup_ide_eclipse"/>.</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Setting up a plain maven project</title>

		<para>
			Eclipse NeoSCADA is built using Eclipse Tycho. It is a set maven
			plugins, which extend maven in a way that the Eclipse PDE type
			projects can be used without much additional changes for maven.
		</para>

		<para>
			This works extremely well in the Eclipse PDE enviroment, but if
			you want to develop a plain maven project you would need to import the
			artifacts manually, and Eclipse NeoSCADA has a lot
			<footnote>
				<para>A the moment of writing it is over 400 OSGi bundles/JAR files.</para>
			</footnote>
			of bundles.
		</para>

		<para>
			The P2 repositories (which is the output of the Eclipse Tycho build) are
			converted to plain maven 2 repositories at the end of the
			build process. Dependencies are generated based on the validating
			target platform of the build. This might not be an optimal solution,
			but creates a working setup without much additional effort.
		</para>

		<para>
			Dependencies to external projects, e.g. the dependencies to Eclipse
			Orbit, are replaced with their Maven Central counterparts (as long as
			they have some).
		</para>

		<para>
			Since Eclipse NeoSCADA 0.3, the generated maven artifacts for all milestones and releases
			are available via maven central under the groupId: <filename>org.eclipse.neoscada.[repo]</filename>.
		</para>

		<para>
			Eclipse NeoSCADA uses Apache Mina for most of its communication
			protocols. Apache Mina uses the maven plugin
			<filename>org.apache.felix:maven-bundle-plugin</filename>
			for providing OSGi bundles. So as soon as you declare a dependency to
			some Eclipse NeoSCADA module which has a dependency to Apache Mina, you
			will need to add this plugin to you setup as well.
		</para>

		<para>
			The reason behind that is, that the <filename>maven-bundle-plugin</filename>
			creates its artifacts with the suffix <filename>.jar</filename>,
			since OSGi bundles are actually JAR files. However it defines the packaging type
			<filename>bundle</filename>
			in the maven POM file of Apache Mina. Now as soon as a dependency is
			declared on an Apache Mina project, Maven tries to resolve that
			dependency using the suffix
			<filename>.bundle</filename>, due to the packaging type <filename>bundle</filename>.
            But that file does not exists, since the correct file extension for
			OSGi bundles is <filename>.jar</filename>.
		</para>

		<para>
			Adding the <filename>maven-bundle-plugin</filename>
			to the build takes care of this behavior. The plugin automatically
			rewrites these requests internally from
			<filename>.bundle</filename> to <filename>.jar</filename>
			and everything works as expected.
		</para>

		<para>
			The following fragment adds the necessary plugin to the build:
			<programlisting language="xml"><![CDATA[...
<plugins>
  <plugin>
    <groupId>org.apache.felix</groupId>
    <artifactId>maven-bundle-plugin</artifactId>
    <extensions>true</extensions>
  </plugin>
</plugins>
...]]></programlisting>
		</para>

		<para>
			A complete minimal project might look like:
			<programlisting language="xml"><xi:include
					href="sample-project.pom"
					parse="text"
					encoding="UTF-8" />
			</programlisting>
		</para>

		<para>
			Also see
			<link xlink:href="https://wiki.eclipse.org/EclipseSCADA/GettingStarted/WithMaven">https://wiki.eclipse.org/EclipseSCADA/GettingStarted/WithMaven</link>
			for additional information.
		</para>
	</section>

</section>

